<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Glossary on Digital Land</title>
    <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Glossary on Digital Land</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Affordable housing</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/affordable-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/affordable-housing/</guid>
      <description>Affordable housing includes social rented, affordable rented and intermediate housing, provided to specified eligible households whose needs are not met by the market. It can be a new-build property or a private sector property that has been purchased for use as an affordable home.
Each year Homes England publish statistics on the supply of affordable homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air quality management</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/air-quality-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/air-quality-management/</guid>
      <description>In an effort to reduce air pollution the Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs have set air quality targets for each local authority.
When a local authority identifies an area where they are at risk of not meeting their target they must set an Air Quality Action Plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aircraft noise</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/aircraft-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/aircraft-noise/</guid>
      <description>Land located close to airports and flight paths may be subject to aircraft noise. This noise is classified in three ways:
 Mechanical noise — rotation of the engine parts, most noticeable when fan blades reach supersonic speeds Aerodynamic noise — from the airflow around the surfaces of the aircraft, especially when flying low at high speeds Noise from aircraft systems — cockpit and cabin pressurization and conditioning systems, and Auxiliary Power units  The Aviation Policy Framework outlines planning considerations with regards to aircraft noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Monuments and Archaeological Sites</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/ancient-monuments-and-archaeological-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/ancient-monuments-and-archaeological-sites/</guid>
      <description>Sites of archaeological or historic importance are protected by the Ancient Monuments and Archaeological Areas Act 1979 and are listed on the National Heritage List for England. This gives them legally protected status.
In order to carry out any work to a scheduled ancient monument or site you will need to apply to Historic England for a Scheduled Monument Consent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual monitoring report</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/annual-monitoring-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/annual-monitoring-report/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Area of archaeologial potential</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/area-of-archaeological-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/area-of-archaeological-potential/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark land value</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/benchmark-land-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/benchmark-land-value/</guid>
      <description>Benchmark land value is the estimated cost of the land given its current use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield sites</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/brownfield-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/brownfield-site/</guid>
      <description>Are often on disused or derelict land. Are more available in the North and Midlands (but most housing demand is in the south east). Are valuable as existing buildings can be split up into more homes on any one site. The site has already been developed so reduces urban sprawl. Use unsightly areas for building developments, so improves the urban environment. Are found in urban areas, so building housing there reduces demand on car use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building age</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/building-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/building-age/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building use</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/building-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/building-use/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community infrastructure levy</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/community-infrastructure-levy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/community-infrastructure-levy/</guid>
      <description>The Community Infrastructure Levy (CIL) is a planning charge, introduced by the Planning Act 2008 as a tool for local authorities in England and Wales to help deliver infrastructure to support the development of their area. It came into force on 6 April 2010 through the Community Infrastructure Levy Regulations 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Con29</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/con29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/con29/</guid>
      <description>The CON29 form has been in use for over 50 years and was created to complement the Local Land Charges Register search. The form contains a standard set of enquiries agreed by central government, the Law Society and local authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation area</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/conservation-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/conservation-area/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contaminated Land</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/contaminated-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/contaminated-land/</guid>
      <description>Land is legally defined as ‘contaminated land’ where substances are causing or could cause:
 significant harm to people, property or protected species significant pollution of surface waters (for example lakes and rivers) or groundwater harm to people as a result of radioactivity  Contaminated land may previously have been used as a:
 factory mine steel mill refinery landfill  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council Tax</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/council-tax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/council-tax/</guid>
      <description>Introduced in the Local Government Finance Act 1992, Council Tax is a tax on domestic property.
There are eight council tax bands (A to H) for which a property will fall into one of based on the property value as determined by the Valuation Office Agency.
The amount of council tax owed for each band is determined by each local authority and various discount or reduction schemes apply, such as a discount for sole occupancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country Park</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/country-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/country-park/</guid>
      <description>A country park is an area designated for people to visit and enjoy recreation in a countryside environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer contributions</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/developer-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/developer-contribution/</guid>
      <description>A policy introduced in the 1990 Town and Country Planning Act means that in order gain planning permission a property developer may be required to provide a contribution to mitigate any impact to local infrastructure.
The contributions can be financial or non-financial. For instance, a developer may be required to provide a percentage of affordable housing within a new property development, or they may be required to provide a financial contribution to increase the intake of a local school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Corporation</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/development-corporation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/development-corporation/</guid>
      <description>Development Corporations are organisations, established byt the Government, for the purpose of urban development. They are often for the development of new surbudan areas or the redevelopment of existing ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Performance Certificate Data</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/energy-performance-certificate-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/energy-performance-certificate-data/</guid>
      <description>Energy Performance Certificates (EPCs) are needed whenever a property is:
 built sold rented  You must order an EPC for potential buyers and tenants before you market your property to sell or rent.
An EPC contains:
 information about a property’s energy use and typical energy costs recommendations about how to reduce energy use and save money  An EPC gives a property an energy efficiency rating from A (most efficient) to G (least efficient) and is valid for 10 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flood zone</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/flood-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/flood-zone/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenbelt</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/greenbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/greenbelt/</guid>
      <description>A policy for controlling urban growth and sprawl. Rings of countryside where urbanisation will be resisted for the foreseeable future, maintaining an area where agriculture, forestry and outdoor leisure can prevail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenfield site</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/greenfield-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/greenfield-site/</guid>
      <description>Greenfield land is undeveloped land in either a city or urban area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gross development value</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/gross-development-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/gross-development-value/</guid>
      <description>Gross development value is the estimated value that a new development could fetch. To work out the gross development value the property developer needs to factor in the percentage of affordable housing that the relevant local authority states in their local plan policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and safety executive</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/health-and-safety-executive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/health-and-safety-executive/</guid>
      <description>The Health and Safety Executive is the body responsible for the encouragement, regulation and enforcement of workplace health, safety and welfare, and for research into occupational risks in Great Britain. It is a non-departmental public body of the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic map vectors</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/historic-map-vectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/historic-map-vectors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing benefit</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/housing-benefit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/housing-benefit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing waiting list</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/housing-waiting-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/housing-waiting-list/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Terrier</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/land-terrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/land-terrier/</guid>
      <description>A land terrier is a record system for an institution&amp;rsquo;s land and property holdings. It differs from a land registry in that it is maintained for the organisation&amp;rsquo;s own needs and may not be publicly accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listed Building</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/listed-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/listed-building/</guid>
      <description>Status attributed to buildings with special architectural or historical interest. Results in additional restrictions being applied in the planning system in an attempt to protect it for future generations. There are categories of listed buildings, called Grades. The higher the grade the more restrictions that apply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local development scheme</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-development-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-development-scheme/</guid>
      <description>Local development schemes are public &amp;lsquo;project plans&amp;rsquo; which identify which local development documents will be produced, in what order and when. It became a statutory requirement for local planning authorities in the UK to produce these schemes under the Planning and Compulsory Purchase Act 2004.
The local development scheme acts as the starting point for the community and stakeholders to find out about the local authority&amp;rsquo;s planning policies in respect to a particular place or issue, and what the status of those policies is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local land charge</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-land-charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-land-charge/</guid>
      <description>A local land charge is a restriction on a piece of land or property that can limit its use or bind the owner to a payment of a sum of money. Charges can include:
 planning decisions road agreements tree preservation orders conservation areas and listed buildings notices environmental health notices charges or objections made against previous owners  A local land charges search will highlight these charges and help you to make an informed choice about buying the parcel of land or property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local plan</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-plan/</guid>
      <description>A local plan sets out local planning policies and identifies how land is used, determining what will be built where. Adopted local plans provide the framework for development across England. Local peoples&amp;rsquo; views are vital in shaping a local plan, helping determine how their community develops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local planning authority</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-planning-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/local-planning-authority/</guid>
      <description>A local planning authority is the local government body that is empowered by law to exercise urban planning functions for a particular area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mineral safeguarding area</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/mineral-safeguarding-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/mineral-safeguarding-area/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Park</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/national-park/</guid>
      <description>Areas in the UK designated under the National Parks and Access to the Countryside Act (2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Planning Policy Framework</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/national-planning-policy-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/national-planning-policy-framework/</guid>
      <description>The revised National Planning Policy Framework (NPPF) was published on July 24th 2018 and sets out government&amp;rsquo;s planning policies for England and how these are expected to be applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net development value</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/net-development-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/net-development-value/</guid>
      <description>The net development value is the estimated amount of money that a property development expects to make once all costs (land value, development, marketing etc) and sales have been taken into consideration.
As a part of the viability assessment a third party may work with a property developer and local authority to ensure that estimates reflect current market values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number of stories</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/number-of-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/number-of-stories/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number of tenancy</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/number-of-tenancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/number-of-tenancy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parking restriction</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/parking-restriction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/parking-restriction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protected View</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/protected-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/protected-view/</guid>
      <description>A protected view or protected vista is the legal requirement within urban planning to preserve the view of a specific place or historic building from another location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radon</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/radon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/radon/</guid>
      <description>Radon is a colourless, odourless radioactive gas. It is formed by the radioactive decay of the small amounts of uranium that occur naturally in all rocks and soils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramsar site</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/ramsar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/ramsar/</guid>
      <description>A Ramsar site is wetlands of international importance designated under the Ramsar Convention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/safeguarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/safeguarding/</guid>
      <description>Safeguarding is an established part of the planning process, designed to ensure that land which has been identified for major infrastructure projects is protected from conflicting developments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 106</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/section-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/section-106/</guid>
      <description>Section 106 is a legal agreement between an property developer and the local planning authority. It is used to mitigate the impact of any new property development to the local community and infrastructure.
The Section 106 agreement contains one or more developer contributions which support the generation of affordable housing, or contribute towards local infrastructure such as green spaces, schools or highway maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site of special scientific interest</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/special-scientific-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/special-scientific-interest/</guid>
      <description>A Site of Special Scientific Interest (SSSI) is a formal conservation designation for an area which is of particular interest because of its fauna, flora or geological or physiological features.
Local authorities are required to have policies within their local plan to protect SSSIs, and should a planning application be submitted either on or close to the site then the appropriate conversation body must be consulted.
Orginally established in the National Parks and Access to the Countryside Act 1949.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenancy deposit</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/tenancy-deposit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/tenancy-deposit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenancy length</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/tenancy-length/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/tenancy-length/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree preservation order</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/tree-preservation-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/tree-preservation-order/</guid>
      <description>A Tree Preservation Order is an order made by a local planning authority in England to protect specific trees, groups of trees or woodlands in the interests of amenity. An Order prohibit the:
 cutting down topping lopping uprooting wilful damage wilful destruction  of trees without the local planning authority’s written consent. If consent is given, it can be subject to conditions which have to be followed. In the Secretary of State’s view, cutting roots is also a prohibited activity and requires the authority’s consent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viability assessement</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/viability-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/viability-assessment/</guid>
      <description>A viability assessment is a part of the planning application process and is used to help a property development and local authority determine a fair developer contribution that will for a section 106 agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ward</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/ward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/ward/</guid>
      <description>Wards in the UK are electoral districts represented by one or more councillors. They are the primary unit of English electoral geography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waste sites</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/waste-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.cloudapps.digital/glossary/waste-sites/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>